SIMMY PAYYAPPILLY VARGHESE

Livermore, California

Phone: 925-523-1393 Email: simmyvarghese5@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/simmyvarghese/ GitHub: https://github.com/simmypayyappillyvarghese Portfolio: https://simmypayyappillyvarghese.github.io/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with 7 years of IT experience in testing and supporting multiple platforms. Recognized for being an enthusiastic learner, team player and problem solver with an eye for details. Passionate about developing apps by utilizing the newly learned technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML,CSS,Javascript,SQL,Handlebars,GraphQL,Markdown

Frameworks/Libraries: Bootstrap, Jquery, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, React, MERN **Tools**: Seguelize (ORM Tool), VS Code, Github, Heroku, Insomnia, Apollo Studio, MySQL

Server Workbench, Mongo DB Compass

PROJECTS

Ecommerce App-Steep Dreams

Github:https://github.com/simmypayyappillyvarghese/steep-dreams

Live Link: https://glacial-fortress-58935.herokuapp.com/

Tools/Languages: MERN Stack(Node Js, Express. js, React, Mongo DB), Graph QL, Semantic

UI

Steep Dreams is an e-commerce website that allows users to register and purchase their favorite teas. Application allows users to sign up ,add products to the cart ,place an order and on Submit navigate to Order summary page.Responsible for creating the queries, mutation and resolvers.Triggered Email Notification for signup and order placement .Responsible for SearchBar functionality and Order Summary Page and rendered all the products placed by the User.

Mixed Music App

Github: https://github.com/simmypayyappillyvarghese/Mixed-Mood

Live Link: https://classique-croissant-67132.herokuapp.com/

Tools/Languages: Bootstrap, Javascript, Express. js, Sequelize, MySql

An MVC Node JS web application for music lovers to choose songs based on their mood and search for songs. Responsible for Creating Login, SignUp Route, Search Routes for

user to search the songs, Save the Song Route to add song to user's library. Created Event Handlers for play the song feature.

California Road Trip Planner

|Github:https://github.com/simmypayyappillyvarghese/California_Road_Trip_Planner

Live Link: https://aaloksikand.github.io/California_Road_Trip_Planner/

Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery, JQuery UI

Web Application created for travelers to plan their trip and find restaurants near their stops.

Responsible for creating Maps and markers for the coordinates using Google MAPS API.Created Route and directions using Direction Services of Maps API and used Yelp API to populate the nearby restaurant data.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer Blackhawk Network

Jul 2021– Oct 2021 Pleasanton,CA

- Built page layouts and email templates according to customer parameters utilizing reusable code using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and JSON.
- Monitored websites utilizing Sentry and Splunk to rectify front-end-related issues.

Systems Support Analyst Blackhawk Network

Dec 2016 – Jul 2021 Pleasanton,CA

- Analyzed and Identified many back end high priority data issues for ETL jobs.
- Created and executed Test plan for the ETL & Digital Format Data load
- Recognized for going the extra mile in supporting multiple internal platforms and conducting knowledge transfer sessions for offshore teams.
- Developed and Maintained SQL scripts to automate data updates.
- Received Appreciation for Improving the efficiency and productivity of the team by automating many manual processes like Data File Archival.

Siebel Tester TechMahindra Limited

Mar 2011 – Mar 2013 Pune.India

- Performed Functional ,Regressional and UI testing of various Siebel products .Maintained test logs and defects for failed test cases.
- Known for collaborating with Developers, E2E and UI Testing teams in identifying defects at an early stage.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Coding Boot Camp Certificate: UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA

MS in Software Engineering: International Technological University, San Jose, CA